He taught him the secret to karate lies in the mind and heart. Not in the hands.
The Karate Kid is a action, adventure, drama film directed by John G. Avildsen.
New Jersey teen Daniel LaRusso moves to Los Angeles with his
mother, and soon strikes up a relationship with Ali.
He quickly finds himself the target of bullying by a group of thugs, led by Ali's ex-boyfriend
Johnny, who study karate at the Cobra Kai dojo under ruthless sensei John Kreese.
Fortunately, Daniel befriends Mr.
Miyagi, an unassuming repairman who just happens to
be a martial arts master himself.
Miyagi takes Daniel under his wing, training him in a more compassionate form of karate for
self-defense and, later, preparing him to compete against the brutal Cobra Kai.
Daniel LaRusso, played by Ralph Macchio.
Mr. Miyagi, played by Pat Morita.
Ali Mills, played by Elisabeth Shue.
Johnny Lawrence, played by William Zabka.
John Kreese, played by Martin Kove.
Lucille LaRusso, played by Randee Heller.
The Karate Kid is a 1984 American martial arts drama film directed by John G.
Avildsen and written by Robert Mark Kamen.
It is the first film in The Karate Kid franchise.
The film stars Ralph Macchio, Pat Morita, Elisabeth Shue, and William Zabka.
The story follows Daniel LaRusso (Macchio), an Italian-American teenager from New Jersey
who moves with his widowed mother to the Reseda neighborhood of Los Angeles.
There, LaRusso encounters harassment from bullies, one of whom is Johnny Lawrence
(Zabka), the ex-boyfriend of LaRusso's love interest, Ali Mills (Shue).
LaRusso is taught karate by a handyman and war veteran named Mr.
Miyagi (Morita) to help LaRusso defend himself and compete
in a karate tournament against his bullies.
Kamen was approached by Columbia Pictures to compose a film similar to Avildsen's
previous success Rocky (1976), after Columbia signed the director.
Kamen drew inspiration from the real-life events of an eight-year-old
Tum Pai student's story in Hawaii when writing the film.
As a result, he maintained strong opinions regarding cast,
and petitioned heavily for Morita's inclusion.
Preparations for the film began immediately after the final edit of the script
was complete, and casting took place between April and June 1983.
Principal photography began on October 31, 1983, in Los
Angeles and was completed by December 16.
The film was Macchio's second major film role, following The Outsiders (1983).
The Karate Kid was theatrically released in the United States on June 22, 1984.
It received positive reviews from critics, many of whom praised the
action sequences, writing, themes, performances, and music.
The film was also a commercial success, grossing over $130 million worldwide, making it one of the
highest-grossing films of 1984 and Hollywood's biggest sleeper hit of the year.
The Karate Kid revitalized the acting career of Morita, who was previously known mostly for comedic
roles, and it earned him a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor.
The film subsequently launched a media franchise and is credited
for popularizing karate in the United States.
The film explores themes of high school,
friendship, martial arts, fight, painting.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.